Guide to the Yale Sustainable Food Project Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Sustainable Food Project records
2003-2016
RU 1068
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10.5
11 boxes
4.9
The records consist of annual reports, original proposal for the Yale farm, broadsides, and calendars of events and activities of the Yale Sustainable Food Project.
Yale Sustainable Food Project
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Yale Sustainable Food Project, 2008-2015.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Computer file formats include Microsoft Word and Adobe PDF.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Sustainable Food Project was founded in 2001 by Yale students, faculty, and staff, President Richard Levin, and chef Alice Waters. The Sustainable Food Project directs a sustainable dining program at Yale, manages an organic farm on campus, and runs diverse programs that support exploration and academic inquiry related to food and agriculture.
In 2003, the first student interns broke ground on Edwards Street and transformed a brambly acre of Farnam Gardens into a productive market garden, now known as the Yale Farm. That summer, they harvested the Farm's first crop and began selling their produce at the New Haven farmers' market. Today, the Farm is a place where students, staff, and area residents gather to eat, work, and learn. It's also a national model for student farms on college campuses and market gardens in urban landscapes.
The year 2003 also marked the inauguration of the Berkeley College dining hall as a test kitchen for serving local, seasonal, and sustainable food to Yale students on a daily basis. The test kitchen demonstrated that it is possible to serve a sustainable menu in all of Yale's colleges. In response to overwhelming student support, the Project was expanded in 2004 to incorporate sustainable food in the menus of all college dining halls. In 2006, they were able to end Berkeley's role as a pilot and begin bringing a greater percentage of sustainable food to each of the colleges. All the college dining halls now serve the same menu, and you can find sustainable food in each of them, at every meal.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of annual reports, original proposal for the Yale farm, broadsides, and calendars of events and activities of the Yale Sustainable Food Project.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Agriculture -- Study and teaching; Food -- Study and teaching; Organic farming; Sustainable agriculture; Yale Sustainable Food Project
- Yale Sustainable Food Project records, 2003-2008; Accession 2008-A-113
  - Annual reports
    - 2005-2006, computer file (PDF)
      General note
      Contact Public Services (phone: 203 432-1735, e-mail: mssa.reference@yale.edu) for information on accessing this digital object.
    - 2006-2007, computer file (PDF)
  - Calendar of events, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Proposal for Yale Organic Farm, 2003; computer file (DOC)
    - Appendix, 2003; computer file (DOC)
- Calendar of events, 2009-2010; Accession 2010-A-029
  - Calendar of events, Fall 2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calendar of events, Spring 2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Calendar of events, 2010; Accession 2011-A-026
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), Fall 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Calendar of events, 2011; Accession 2011-A-041
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), Spring 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Calendar of events, 2011; Accession 2012-A-019
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), Fall 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Calendar of events, 2012; Accession 2012-A-032
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), Spring 2012 (Box 1)
- Calendar of events, 2012; Accession 2013-A-016
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), Fall 2012 (Box 1)
- Calendar of events and pamphlet, 2013; Accession 2014-A-031
  - Calendar of events, 2013 fall (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Food and Agriculture at Yale: Courses, Resources and Opportunities, 2013 fall (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Calendar of events, 2014 Spring; Accession 2014-A-054
  - Poster with calendar of events (2 copies), 2014 Spring (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Broadside, 2015; Accession 2016-A-026
  - Broadside, "Chewing the Fat", 2 copies, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Broadside, 2016; Accession 2017-A-024
  - Broadside, "Chewing the Fat," 2 copies, 2016 Fall (Box 1)